Guide to the Jon Butler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Jon Butler papers
1963-2011
MS 1982
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
13.5
28 boxes
15257.6
The papers consist of lecture and course notes; research materials; writings; and departmental files documenting the professional career of historian Jon Butler as educator, administrator, and author.
Butler, Jon, 1940-
Biographical / Historical
Jon Harold Butler was born June 4, 1940. He received a B.A. (1964) and a Ph.D. (1972) from the University of Minnesota. He was assistant professor of history at California State College, Bakersfield (1971-1975) and at the University of Illinois at Chicago (1975-1985). Butler has served in numerous capacities at Yale University: Professor of American Studies, History, and Religious Studies (1985-1990); Chair of the American Studies Program (1988-1993); William Robertson Coe Professor of American Studies and History (1990-2004); Director of Graduate Studies, American Studies Program (1995-1997); Director of the Division of Humanities, Faculty of Arts and Sciences (1997-1999); Chair, Department of History (1999-2004); Dean, Graduate School of Arts and Sciences (2004-2010); Acting University Librarian (2010 December-2011 July); and Howard R. Lamar Professor of American Studies, History, and Religious Studies (2004-present).
Conditions Governing Access
The papers are closed to researchers, excluding the donor and the following family members: Roxanne Butler, Benjamin Butler, and Peter Butler, and Caroline Butler and Naomi Butler and other sons and daughters of Benjamin and Peter as yet unborn, until January 1, 2035, or upon the death of Jon Butler, whichever occurs first, at which time the papers shall be open to all researchers.
Boxes 6-8, student papers, are closed to researchers for the life of the student plus five years (5) or seventy-five (75) years from the date the student graduates or withdraws from the University, whichever is longer.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Custodial History
Gift of Jon Butler, 2011.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in four series: I. Personal Files, 1963-1992. II. Teaching Files, 1983-2010. III. Professional Files, 1972-2011. IV. Writings, 1973-2004. Series V. Electronic Records, 1994-2011.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of lecture and course notes; research materials; writings; departmental files; and electronic records documenting the professional career of historian Jon Butler as educator, administrator, and author.
Protestant churches -- History; Religion historians; United States -- Religion -- History; Butler, Jon, 1940-; Yale University. Department of History; Yale University -- Faculty
- Personal Files, 1963-1992, undated; Series I
  - General
    - Curricula vitae/copyright, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Newberry Library Family and Community History Summer Training Institute, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University of Minnesota course work of Jon Butler
    Scope and Contents
    Course work includes bibliographies, research materials, and book reviews written by Jon Butler.
    - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - Circa 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Circa 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Renaissance, Circa 1965-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Va" paper, 1965-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Research materials and papers on ministers and baptism in seventeenth-century Virginia.
    - Dissertation correspondence, 1966, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Rutman, Darrett (resource?), Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Darrett Rutman was one of Butler's dissertation advisers.
- Teaching Files, 1983-2010; Series II
  - Course materials
    Arrangement
    Course materials are arranged alphabetically by course title and chronologically therein.
    - AmSt (American Studies) 189 / Hist 111
      - 1989 fall (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1990 fall (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Syllabi for AmSt 189, 190, and 191, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Course Improvement Form, 1989 fall (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - AmSt 311a - Rel St (Religious Studies) 301a, 1985 fall (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - AmSt 312
      - 1986 spring (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - 1989 spring (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 311/312 syllabi (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - 1994 spring (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - AmSt 312b
      - 1989 fall (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 1995 spring (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - 1996 spring (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - 1997 spring (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1999 spring (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 2000 spring (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Course evaluation, 2000 spring (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - 2001 spring (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - 2002 spring (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - 2002 spring (disc section) (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - 2002 spring (teaching evaluation) (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - 2003 spring (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - 2004 spring (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - AmSt 390
      - 1986 fall (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - 1991 junior seminar syllabi (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - AmSt 426a, 1995 fall (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - AmSt 431, 1987 spring (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - AmSt 434 mid-term course, improvement forms, Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - AmSt 700
      - 1989 fall (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - 1991 spring (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - 1994 fall (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - 2003 fall (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - AmSt 702b-Hist 705b - Transformation of America, 1680-1770, 1995 spring (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - AmSt 705
      - 1985 fall (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - 1986 fall (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - 1988 fall (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - 1989 spring (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1990 spring (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1991 spring (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1992 spring (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 1992 fall (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 1993 spring (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 1994 spring (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 1999 fall (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - AmSt 705a/Hist 705a/Rel St 705a
      - 1988 fall (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - 1998 fall (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - 2000 fall (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - AmSt 705b
      - 1998 spring (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - AmSt 705/Hist 720/Rel St 705
      - 2006 spring (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - 2007 spring (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - AmSt 706
      - 1986 spring (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - AmSt 707
      - 1987 spring (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - AmSt 721a, research seminar
      - 1998 fall (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Hist 002/004
      - 2004 fall (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - 2005 fall (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - 2006 fall (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - 2007 fall (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - 2008 fall (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - 2009 fall (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - 2010 spring (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Hist 101, Rev America
      - 2002 fall (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - 2003 fall (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Hist 114, New World Civ 1400-1770
      - 1985 winter (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Hist 115 New World Civ 1770-1898
      - 1985 spring (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Hist 145b/AmSt 312b/RelSt 294b
      - Course evaluations, 1993 spring (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Hist 720
      - 2008 spring (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Hist 721
      - 2001 fall (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - 2002 fall (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - 2005 spring (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - 2009 spring (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hist 750, Religion and Modernity
      - 2001 fall (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - RelSt 490, Approaches to the Study of Religion
      - 1999 fall (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lectures on U. S. history (1600-1865), 1985-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Student papers and records
    Student papers are arranged alphabetically by student name. Folders may also contain related correspondence.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Boxes 6-8, student papers, are restricted until January 1, 2086 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Abrams, Elizabeth, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Avery, James, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Bennett, James, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Braude, Ann/Behre, Patricia, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Brown, David C., 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Bruce, Marcus, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Bryant, Joan, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Casper, Scott, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Chet, Guy, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Chua, Susan, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Cormode, Scott, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - D'Aoust, Ian, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Dietsche, Mary Lynn, 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Douglas, Davison, 1983, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Echols, James, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Flaherty, Martin, 1984-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Gedge, Karin Erdevig, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Gest, Maureen, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Grasso, Christopher, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Hermes, Katherine, 1991-1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Hunter, Judith, 1986-1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Jenkins, Tom, 1986-1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Lief, Edward R., 1998 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Maffly-Kipp, Laurie, 1985-1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - McAlister, Elizabeth, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - McKee,Joshua, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - McLeod, Rebecca, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Occult Seminar (Elizabeth Arnold), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - O"Mellin, Liam, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Oppenheimer, Mark, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Parks, Nancy Neims, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Renville, Roger, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Robinson, Jacqueline, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Rozario, Kevin, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sabin, Margaret, 1988, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Satter, Beryl, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Wachter, Phyllis E., 1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Senior essays, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Student recommendations, 1986-1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Professional Files, 1972-2011; Series III
  - Academic program reviews
    - Classics Department, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - English Department, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Graduate School, 1998 summer (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Religious Studies, 1995-2005 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - UCLA History Department, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - American Studies
    - Chairman, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1978, 1988-1993 (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
      Files include correspondence, reports, enrollment statistics, administrative procedures, and related topics.
    - National Endowment for the Humanities grant, "New World Civilizations", 1985 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Newsletter and program brochures, 1985, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Senior administrative secretary position, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Cal State Bakersfield, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, lectures, and symposia
    Files are arranged in chronological order.
    Files may contain papers presented, research materials, printed ephemera, and related correspondence for events in which Butler served as either chairperson, presenter, moderator, committee member, or attendee.
    - Organization of American Historians (OAH), 1978 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Paper presented by Butler, "The Huguenots in New York and South Carolina: An Essay in Ethnic Pathology"
    - Social Science History Association (SSHA), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Paper presented by Butler, "The Ethnic Mirage: Defining and Testing Ethnicity and Religious Loyalty in a Pre-Independent America."
    - Conference at the University of Pennsylvania Celebrating the Tercentenary of Pennsylvania, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Paper presented by Butler, "A Spiritual Tower of Babel: Shifting Structure and Functions of Religious Diversity in Colonial Pennsylvnia, 1680-1760."
    - OAH, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Krefeld Conference, Cologne, Germany, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Symposium on Religious Awakenings, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - American Historical Association (AHA), "Beyond Clericalism", 1983 December (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Revisioning America Symposium,"Sacralization of the Colonial American Landscape", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Newberry Refugee Conference, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "The Revocation of the Edict of Nantes and Huguenot Migration to South Carolina", 1985 October (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Lecture by Butler at Clemson commemorating the 300th anniversary of the Revocation of the Edict of Nantes.
    - "People and Societies in Flight," Newberry Renaissance Center, conference, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Distinguished Visiting Scholars Lecture Series, University of Notre Dame, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Lecture by Butler, "American Catholicism and a New Religious History."
    - United States Capitol Historical Society, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Conference on Tocqueville's Democracy in America, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - American Society of Church History, New York Annual Meeting, 1990 December (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - American Religious History Workshop, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Pennsylvania State University/German Historical Institute Conference on Cultural Transfer (A. G. Roeber paper), 1992 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - AHA Session Proposal, Born-Again History?, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Southern Historical Association, "Southern Spiritual Hothouse", 1994 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Judaic Studies Center, University of Pennsylvania, 1997 April (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Huguenot Conference, College of Charleston, 1997 May (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Omohundro Institute of Early American History and Culture Fourth Annual Conference/Rutman's session (Chair: Jon Butler), 1998 June (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Henry Luce Foundation (sponsored discussion), 1999 January (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Lilly Seminar on Religion and Higher Education, University of Notre Dame, 1999 March (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - University of Colorado lecture, 1999 October (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - American Antiquarian Society (AAS), 1999 November (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - European Social Science History Conference, Amsterdam, 2000 April (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Women of the Atlantic World in the Age of Religious Reform and Revival Conference, University of Cambridge, 2000 April (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Washington, D. C. dinner, 2000 June (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Conference on New York State History, Fordham, 2000 June (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Panel, 2000 July (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Rituals and Spirits: Religious Contact and Change in the Early Atlantic World," symposium, University of Florida, 2000 October (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Southern Historical Association Conference, 2000 November (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Princeton symposium, 2000 November (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - American Academy of Religion (AAR), 2000 November (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - OAH lecture series, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "Interpreting the American Catholic Experience: The Achievement of Jay P. Dolan," conference, University of Notre Dame, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - National Park Service/OAH, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - PBS, Philadelphia, 2004 January (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - AHA, Washington, D.C., 2004 January (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Kaplan Conference, Stanford, 2004 February (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Society of American Historians, 2004 March (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - NEH Forum on American History, Culture and Ideas in the Colonial and Founding Period, Washington, D.C., 2004 April (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Slifka Panel, 2004 October (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Vassar lecture, 2004 November (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Council of Graduate Schools (CGS), Washington, D.C., 2004 December (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - AHA conference, Seattle, 2005 January (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Indiana University lecture, 2005 February (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Lebanon Valley College lecture, Pennsylvania, 2005 March 15 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Jews and the American Republic Conference, 2005 March 20-21 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - OAH, San Francisco, 2005 March 31-April 3 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Mellon Graduate Education Project, Princeton, 2005 April (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Responsive PH.D. Conference Panel, 2005 June (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - History and Theory Religion and History Conference, Wesleyan, 2005 November (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Columbia University, Middle States Commission on Higher Education, Reaccreditation Visiting Committee, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - China trip, 2007 July (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Japan trip, 2008 March (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Secular age conference, 2008 April (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Beijing Foreign Studies University, 2008 July (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Teagle Foundation Conference, 2008 August (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - OAH, Rockford, Illinois, 2008 November (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - American and Iranian Studies Seminar, England, 2008 December (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Gustave O. Arlt Award, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Thulin lecture, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2009 March (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Indiana University Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI) Conference, 2009 June (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Beijing, China trip, 2009 July (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Dordt, Sioux Center, Iowa, 2010 March (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - American Jewish Historical Society Conference, 2010 June (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Salt Lake Sunstone Symposium and Workshops, 2010 August (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary Workshop, 2010 October (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Teaching American History Symposium, Newberry Library, Chicago, 2010 December (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - AHA, 2011 January (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Montana State University, Bozeman, 2011 January (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - OAH, 2011 March (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - TAH, Harrisburg, 2011 June (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - American Religious Architecture: A Symposium Devoted to the Architecture, Decoration and Cultural Context of American Places of Worship, Undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence
    - 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 2005-2006 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 2007-2008 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 2009-2010 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Topical files
    - Edwards Center, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Edwards, Jonathan, Works of, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Graduate Employees and Students Organization (GESO) at Yale/GESO strike, 1991-2003 (Box 17, Folder 6-9)
    - History Department
      - Faculty files, 1995-2005 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Garcia, Mario, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Woodward, C. Vann, plaque, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Humanities Advisory Committee (HAC), 1997-1999 (Box 18, Folder 4-8)
    - OAH nominating board, 2005-2008 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Pew Program in Religion and American History
      Files contain correspondence, annual reports, draft proposals, budgets, "Pew Notes," and related materials.
      - 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - 1991-1997 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - 1993-1994 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
      - 1995-1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - 1996-1998 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Cormode report, Undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Tenure reviews (non-Yale), 1984-1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - TF (Teaching Fellow-Levels I-II), 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
    - University of Illinois
      - Chicago Circle business, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Course evaluations for Butler, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Professional activities of Butler, 1975-1984 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - 1743 Yorkshire Visitation, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Statistics, colonial churches, 1990, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Weis-computerized files (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - William and Mary Quarterly, 1992-1995 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      Files contain correspondence, monthly/quarterly reports, guidelines for publication, statistics, and related materials from Butler's tenure as a member of the editorial board, 1992-1995, and as chair of the board, 1994-1995.
    - William and Mary Quarterly and the Institute of Early American History and Culture, 1990-1995 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Files contain correspondence, meeting minutes, annual reports, and related materials from Butler's tenure as member of the Council of the Institute of Early American History and Culture, 1992-1995, and secretary, 1994-1995.
- Writings, 1973-2004; Series IV
  - General files
    Files contain reproductions and negatives of photographs used in Butler's published work. Listed by plate # and/or chapter number.
    - Plates (book)
      Arranged by plate number. There is no plate 13.
      - #1-Glastonburg Tor (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - #2-The Art How to Know Men (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - #3- Anatomy 1729 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - #4-Old Trinity Church, Maryland (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - #5- #6 Old Ships Meeting House (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - #7-Stiles-Brenton Point inscription (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - #8-New York City view, 1679-1680 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - #9-New York City view, 1730 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - #10-Saint James, Goose Creek (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - #11-Whitefield, The SchemingTriumvirate (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - #12-Whitefield crypt (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - #14-Johannes Kelpius (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - #15-Joseph Smith's green sea stone (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - #16-St. Thomas Church, Philadelphia (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - #17-Cincinnati, 1859 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - American Historical Review publications, Undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Chapters
      Arranged by chapter number in which item appears.
      - 1-The Old Plantation (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - 2-Pownall, "A Design to Represent the Beginning...." (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - 3-Powder horn from Seven Years War (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - 4-The Four Indian Kings (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - 4-Samuel Harrison's plantation (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - 4-Turner House, Salem (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - 4-Wood-framed houses of laboring people (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - 4-Mulberry Plantation slave quarters (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - 4-Westover, river front facade (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - 4-Copley, Paul Revere (Box 21, Folder 26)
      - 4-Library bookcase, Charleston (Box 21, Folder 27)
      - 4-German "schrank" (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - 4-Virginia courthouse (Box 21, Folder 29)
      - 4-Chief magistrate's chair, North Carolina (Box 21, Folder 30)
      - 4-New York City Hall, 1745-1747 (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - 4-Masonic Master's chair (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - 4-Second Grand Anniversary Procession (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - 5-New Haven Green in 1800 (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - 5-Myer Myers, torah finials (Box 21, Folder 35)
      - 6-Portraits of Benjamin Franklin (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Articles, review essays, and book chapters
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "Africans' Religions in British America, 1650-1840", 1998-1999 (Box 22, Folder 1)